Guide to the International Association records, 1961-1987
Duke University. University Archives
International Association records 1961-1987
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. International Association.
0.5 linear feet Extent: 500 Items
The International Association is an apolitical, non-religious student organization that promotes socio-cultural relations among American and International students. The collection contains miscellaneous correspondence, clippings, announcements, list of past president and members, newsletters, and other materials pertaining to international student associations at Duke, nationally, and at other schools. Materials in the collection range in date from 1961-1987.
uaforstu
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The International Association records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1978, 1989.
Historical Note
taken from International Association's homepage http://www.duke.edu/web/intlassoc/about_us.html
The International Association spun off International Club, which was formed in the mid-1950s as an organization to provide social programming for graduate and undergraduate international students. Since the name change, the International Association has centered its goals on the integration of the international and American communities at Duke.
The International Council was derived from the International Association in 1999, as international students became increasingly aware that a variety of their administrative needs, from holiday housing to liaisons between Duke's myriad cultural groups, were still sadly lacking. The International Council then joined forces with DSG (Duke Student Government) to create an entity that would "act as an advisory board to DSG and as a lobbying organization representing international students in front of the administration."
Beginning in fall 2001, the International Association and the International Council began to function as a conglomerate with the purpose of developing and promoting internationalism at Duke, inculcating the diverse cultures of international students in the Duke Community and spreading political and non-political awareness of issues affecting their daily lives.
Collection Overview
The collection contains miscellaneous correspondence, clippings, announcements, list of past president and members, newsletters, and other materials pertaining to international student associations at Duke, nationally, and other at schools. Materials in the collection range in date from 1961-1987.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. International Association.; Duke University. International Club.; Duke University. International Council.; Graduate students, Foreign -- North Carolina -- Durham.; Students, Foreign -- North Carolina -- Durham.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.)
Related Material
AIESEC, Duke University Chapter records, 1966-1970.
University Archives. Duke University.
International House records, 1957-[ongoing].
University Archives. Duke University.
International Studies Center records, 1952-1957.
University Archives. Duke University.
Joseph C. Wetherby papers, 1930-1976.
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - Administrative Procedures, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Annual Records, 1964-1970 (includes minutes)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1978
  - Elections, 1975-1976
  - Emergency Fund, 1978, undated.
  - Financial Ledger, 1969-1971
  - Financial Statements, 1969-1977
  - International Evening Event, 1976
  - L'Atitude, 1987 (an international cultural magazine produced by Duke undergraduates)
  - List of Presidents, 1961-1990
  - Membership Lists, 1973-1978
  - Minutes, 1971-1977
  - Miscellaneous
  - Newsletter, 1975, undated
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1973-1986
  - Project Latin America, 1969
  - Proposals, 1986
  - Social Events, 1962-1980